<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Warsaw Tour Top 10</string>
    <string name="category_old_town">Old Town</string>
    <string name="category_fryderyk_chopin">Fryderyk Chopin\'s Warsaw</string>
    <string name="category_rising_museum">Warsaw Rising Museum</string>
    <string name="category_palace_of_cul_and_sci">Palace of Culture and Science</string>
    <string name="category_royal_residences">Royal Residences</string>
    <string name="category_judaica">Judaica</string>
    <string name="category_copernicus">Copernicus Science Centre</string>
    <string name="category_national_museum">National Museum in Warsaw</string>
    <string name="category_vistula">Vistula</string>
    <string name="category_pge_narodowy">PGE Narodowy stadium</string>
    <string name="old_town_header_body_text">Priceless historic site inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List</string>
    <string name="old_town_body_text">The history of the Warsaw Old Town goes back over 700 years. Razed to the ground during World War II, the Old Town has been reconstructed from scratch. UNESCO has inscribed it on its list of World Cultural Heritage. The Royal Castle is one of the most eagerly visited attractions in Warsaw. It offers valuable exhibits, such as royal thrones. At the foot of the Castle, from the Vistula River side, there are meticulously renovated Kubicki Arcades and two-level gardens. In summertime, the Old Town is filled with coffee gardens and numerous cultural festivals are held in the Old and New Town Squares, the Castle courtyard and the Arcades. In winter, the Old Town and the Royal Route glitter with captivating illuminations. The king Zygmunt column towers over the square. Raised in the 17 th century and 22 metres high, it is the oldest and the highest monument in Warsaw. It honours king Zygmunt III Waza, who in 1596 moved the capital from Kraków to Warsaw. The statue fell during World War II and its present column was erected in 1949. The monument is always surrounded by crowds of people. This is where everyone making appointments in the Old Town meets.</string>
    <string name="old_town_header">Old Town</string>
    <string name="see_on_a_map">see on a map</string>
    <string name="map">Map</string>
    <string name="old_town_content_description">Light blue background</string>
    <string name="worth_seeing">Worth seeing!</string>
    <string name="mermaid_statue"><b>Mermaid Statue</b> – a guardian and symbol of Warsaw standing in the Old Town Square. The second one is located near the Świętokrzyski Bridge, but the statues of half woman half fish can be found around the city.</string>
    <string name="paintings_by_rembrandt"><b>Paintings by Rembrandt, Royal Castle Museum pl. Zamkowy 4</b>, \"Girl in a Picture Frame\" and \"A Scholar at his Writing Table\" – works of the Dutch master in the Lanckoroński Gallery.</string>
    <string name="royal_castle_page"><u>www.zamek-krolewski.pl/en</u></string>
    <string name="hidden_in_the_basements"><b>Hidden in the basements</b> – Old Town basements form the Route of the Old Town Cultural Basements. They can be reached from a number of places, e.g. at the Museum of Warsaw (Rynek Starego Miasta 28-42) and at ul. Brzozowa 11/13 (Hertiage Interpretation Centre). In the crypt of the Cathedral Basilica (ul. Świętojańska 8) there are tombs of the last Polish king Stanisław August Poniatowski, outstanding pianist and politician Ignacy Jan Paderewski and many others.</string>
    <string name="worth_trying">Worth trying!</string>
    <string name="wuzetka_and_zygmuntowka"><b>Wuzetka and Zygmuntówka cakes.</b> Sweet symbols of Warsaw can be bought in cake shops around the city, although they taste best served in cosy Old Town cafes.</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_content_description">Cyan background</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_header">Fryderyk Chopin\'s Warsaw</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_header_page">en.chopin.warsawtour.pl</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_header_body_text">The genius composer, Fryderyk Chopin spent half of his life in Warsaw.</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_body_text">This is where he grew up, was educated and composed many of his masterpieces. Multimedia benches are signposts that help follow his footsteps. Every one of them signifies a site that was meaningful to the composer.</string>
    <string name="worth_listening">Worth listening!</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_concert">Concerts at the foot of the Chopin Monument, the Royal Łazienki (entrance at Aleje Ujazdowskie)</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_royal_lazienki"><u>www.lazienki-krolewskie.pl/en</u></string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_concert_text">Concerts are held every Sunday at noon and 4 p.m., from mid-May till the end of September. Chopin’s music may also be listened to at the most important concert halls in Warsaw, e.g. during the annual \"Chopin and his Europe\" International Music Festival.</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_festiwal_page"><u>www.festiwal.nifc.pl/en/</u></string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_museum">Fryderyk Chopin Museum, ul. Okólnik 1</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_museum_page"><u>chopin.museum/en</u></string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_museum_text">Modern, multimedia, interactive and full of brilliant Chopin-related exhibits. Here you can see the composer\'s last piano, his candy box, his death mask, hand cast, etc.</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_church">The Church of the Holy Cross on the Royal Route ul. Krakowskie Przedmieście 3</string>
    <string name="fryderyk_chopin_church_text">The urn containing Chopin’s heart, brought from France by the composer’s beloved sister, is immured in the left pillar of the main nave of the church.</string>
    <string name="rising_museum_header">Warsaw Rising Museum</string>
    <string name="rising_museum_header_page">www.1944.pl/en</string>
    <string name="rising_museum_header_body_text">One of the most modern and most frequently visited of all Warsaw museums.</string>
    <string name="rising_museum_body_text"><b>This is an expression of homage paid by Varsovians to those who fought and died for a free Poland and her capital.</b> The multimedia exhibition shows the struggle and daily lives of insurgents against the backdrop of dread under Nazi occupation, and tells the story of post-war communist terror and the fate of the Uprising’s survivors in the Polish People’s Republic. Lectures, film screenings, theatrical performances and concerts take place here: the greatest number of events are held during the week immediately preceding August 1st – the anniversary of the first day of the 1944 armed insurgence against the Nazi occupants.</string>
    <string name="worth_knowing">Worth knowing!</string>
    <string name="rising_museum_every_year"><b>Every year, on August 1st at 5:00 p.m.</b> sirens are sounded, and all pedestrian and street traffic stops for one minute. This is how Warsaw remembers her insurgents.</string>
    <string name="worth_hearing">Worth hearing!</string>
    <string name="rising_museum_the_pounding_heart"><b>The Pounding heart of Warsaw</b> resounding from a metal monument at the museum. Its walls bear an engraved calendar commemorating 63 days of fights.</string>
    <string name="rising_museum_murals"><b>Murals by leading graphic artists</b> in the Wall of Art, an open-air gallery located in the Rose Garden right by the museum.</string>
    <string name="rising_museum_liberator"><b>Liberator B-24J bomber</b> – a plane that brought help to the insurgents was shot down on its way back to the base. Its full size replica is one of the main attractions of the museum.</string>
    <string name="rising_museum_city_of_ruins"><b>Miasto Ruin (City of Ruins)</b> – a film in 3D. A digital reconstruction of the destroyed city seen from the flight deck of a B-24 Liberator.</string>
    <string name="web_page">Web page</string>
    <string name="teal_background">Teal background</string>
    <string name="grean_background">Grean background</string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_header">Palace of Culture and Science</string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_header_body_text">One of the most recognisable buildings in Warsaw</string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_body_text">This building, a perfect example of socialist-realist architecture, can be seen from every part of the city. For many it serves as the actual signpost. It houses over 3000 rooms and is home to almost 90 \"residents\" such as 4 theatres, a cinema, 2 orchestras, 3 museums and a Warsaw Tourist Information Point. The 45th floor is also home to a couple of peregrine falcons called Wars and Sawa. An ornithological reality show featuring them can be seen at</string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_peregrinus_page"><u>www.webcam.peregrinus.pl</u></string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_body_text_two">The Palace of Culture and Science was erected as \"a gift from the Soviet people\", though gossip had it that it was \"a gift from Stalin\" and thus a symbol of the Soviet domination.</string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_the_palace"><b>The Palace</b> from basements to roof. The tour includes the labyrinth of subterranean corridors, ballrooms, and the viewing deck on the 30th floor.</string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_horyzont_historii">How Warsaw looked like in the Middle Ages and subsequent periods. Come and see it for yourself going on a virtual journey in time <b>#HoryzontHistorii</b>, put on VR goggles and let the adventure begin.</string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_and_science"><b>The Palace of Culture and Science</b> is the tallest building in Poland with 237m from its foundation to the spire and 44 floors!</string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_tower_clock"><b>Tower clock</b> known as the Millenium Clock was unveiled on the New Year\'s Eve night 2000/2001. Its every face has 6m in diameter! A miniature replica of the clock is in the main hall of the Palace.</string>
    <string name="palace_of_culture_historic_monument"><b>A historic monument</b> - in 2007 the Palace was inscribed on the list of historic monuments, thus enjoying the same kind of protection as the Royal residences and the Old Town.</string>
    <string name="light_grean_background">Light green background</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_header">Royal residences</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_lazienki_header_body_text">The Royal Łazienki</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_lazienki_page"><u>www.lazienki-krolewskie.pl/en</u></string>
    <string name="royal_residences_lazienki_body_text">The residence of Poland’s last king is one of the most attractive palace and park complexes in Europe. The complex name Łazienki (baths in English) derives from 17th century baths of Polish nobleman that were reconstructed into a palace in 18th century. Located in the very heart of the city, the park is made up of three gardens: the Royal, Belvedere, and Modernist. Their joint area is an amazing 76 hectares! Squirrels, ducks, peacocks and swans all call it home. Numerous sculptures embellish the park as well. In the Palace on the Isle, king Stanisław August Poniatowski held the famous Thursday lunches for scientists and poets to discuss ongoing events. Today the Palace serves as a museum housing the royal collection of paintings.</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_lazienki_park"><b>All the park’s landmarks</b>, including the Old Orangery with unique wooden Royal Theatre, the Myślewicki Palace, the Officer Cadets School and the Belvedere.</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_lazienki_amphitheatre"><b>The amphitheatre</b> imitating the ruins of the Forum Romanum.</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_wilanow_header_body_text">Museum of King Jan III’s Palace at Wilanów</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_wilanow_page"><u>www.wilanow-palac.pl/en</u></string>
    <string name="royal_residences_wilanow_body_text">The Wilanów Palace was built by king Jan III Sobieski, a brave monarch and an outstanding commander, a victorious warrior of the Battle of Vienna. Its design was inspired by French baroque residences. The plot of land between the palace and the Wilanów Lake is home to a two-level Italian garden with a romantic park in the southern corner kept in the English style. Nicknamed \"the Polish Versailles\", the Palace is one of the most beautiful ones in Europe.</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_wilanow_glass_pavilion"><b>A glass pavilion</b> in the shape of a Turkish tent, full of valuable sculptures.</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_wilanow_poster_museum"><b>The Poster Museum</b> at the old riding arena.</string>
    <string name="royal_residences_wilanow_summer_residence"><b>King’s favourite summer residence.</b> This is where king Jan III Sobieski relaxed in the company of his beloved wife, Queen Marie Casimire. The assets of the Palace were also appreciated by its subsequent owners, for instance Alexandra and Stanisław Kostka Potocki, who opened the first Polish art museum here in 1805.</string>
    <string name="lime_background">Lime background</string>
    <string name="judaica_header">Judaica</string>
    <string name="judaica_header_body_text">Before World War II, Jews accounted for 30 per cent of Warsaw residents.</string>
    <string name="judaica_body_text">Writer and Noble Prize laureate Isaac Bashevis Singer, writer, doctor and teacher Janusz Korczak, actress Estera Rachela Kamińska and composer Władysław Szpilman all lived here. There were hundreds of Jewish schools and libraries, and over 130 newspaper titles. There were also theatres and sports clubs. The following monuments are reminders of the Holocaust: the Route Recalling the Martyrdom and the Struggle of the Jews, leading from Umschlagplatz at ul. Stawki to the Ghetto Uprising Monument at ul. Zamenhofa and cast iron plaques delineating the ghetto boundaries on the pavement.</string>
    <string name="worth_visiting">Worth visiting!</string>
    <string name="judaica_polin_header">POLIN - Museum of the History of Polish Jews, \n6 Anielewicza Street</string>
    <string name="judaica_polin_page"><u>www.polin.pl/en</u></string>
    <string name="judaica_polin_body">The story of one thousand years of common Polish-Jewish history, told in a symbolic location. The exhibition includes eight multimedia galleries: early medieval settlements, turbulent events over the centuries, the Holocaust and the post-1989 renaissance of Jewish communities.</string>
    <string name="judaica_polin_grzybowski_square"><b>Plac Grzybowski (Grzybowski Square),</b> the centre of Jewish culture in Warsaw. The Nożyk synagogue overlooks neighbouring Twarda Street. Próżna, the only surviving street of the pre-war Jewish district, leads off the square at a right angle.</string>
    <string name="judaica_ghetto_wall"><b>Between Sienna and Złota streets,</b> the last two fragments of the ghetto wall has been preserved. To see it, enter the courtyard from ul. Złota 62.</string>
    <string name="judaica_festivals"><b>Warsaw hosts festivals of Jewish culture</b>\n\"Singer’s Warsaw\" in August,</string>
    <string name="judaica_festivals_singer_page"><u>www.festiwalsingera.pl/en</u></string>
    <string name="judaica_festivals_film">\"Warsaw Jewish Film Festival\" in October,</string>
    <string name="judaica_festivals_film_page"><u>www.wjff.pl/en/</u></string>
    <string name="judaica_festivals_anniversary"><b>Every year, on April 19th,</b> the anniversary of the Ghetto Uprising, daffodils are given out on the streets as a symbol of memory, respect and hope.</string>
    <string name="yellow_background">Yellow background</string>
    <string name="copernicus_header">Copernicus Science Centre</string>
    <string name="copernicus_header_body_text">A kingdom of experiments and a heaven for the world-curious.</string>
    <string name="copernicus_body_text"><b>Here everyone can delve into nature’s mysteries, conduct experiments on their own and, above all, have fun.</b> In CSC nobody asks for a tour guide! As assumed by the Centre founders, everyone should feel here like a researcher and a discoverer, who never experiment to anybody\'s dictation. The exposition is divided into theme galleries. Experiment stands are located also in the nearby Explorer\'s Park right by the Vistula River bank. On summer weekends, after dark, the Park houses an open-air cinema with a scientific repertoire.</string>
    <string name="copernicus_experimenting"><b>Experimenting</b> is so enthralling that you should reserve a good couple of hours for visiting the Copernicus Science Centre. As the \"Copernicus\" is forever popular, to avoid standing in long queues consider buying tickets online at</string>
    <string name="copernicus_tickets_page"><u>www.bilety.kopernik.org.pl</u></string>
    <string name="copernicus_heavens"><b>The \"Heavens of Copernicus\"</b> allows visitors to experience the furthest depths of space. Tickets to the Planetarium are separate. As film screenings are made in full darkness, latecomers will not be admitted.</string>
    <string name="amber_background">Amber background</string>
    <string name="national_museum_header">National Museum in Warsaw</string>
    <string name="national_museum_header_body_text">One of the largest and most extensive collections in Poland.</string>
    <string name="national_museum_body_text"><b>Its holdings amount to over 800,000 exhibits of both Polish and foreign art dating from antiquity until now.</b> These are paintings, sculptures, drawings, works on paper, photographs, coins as well as objects of applied art and interior design. The National Museum in Warsaw is also one of the most modern museums in Europe. Computer controlled LED lighting is a feature of only a few museums and galleries in Germany and the United Kingdom. The LED system makes it possible to adjust light intensity to every painting separately so that its unique qualities are enhanced.</string>
    <string name="national_museum_battle_of_grunwald"><b>Bitwa pod Grunwaldem</b> (The Battle of Grunwald) by Jan Matejko - the largest Polish painting: the canvas is nearly 40 m2 (4.26 x 9.87 m) in size. It took 400 climbing ropes to remove the painting from the wall.</string>
    <string name="national_museum_faras_galery"><b>Faras Galery</b> - the only exhibition of in Europe featuring Medieval Nubian paintings, cultural artefacts and artworks from the Christian period.</string>
    <string name="national_museum_medieval_art_gallery"><b>Medieval Art Gallery</b> with works of art from all regions historically connected with Poland and created in other parts of Europe.</string>
    <string name="national_museum_gallery_of_art"><b>Gallery of art of the 20th and 21st centuries</b> - one of the largest collections of modern and contemporary art in Poland.</string>
    <string name="national_museum_temporary_exhibition"><b>Interesting temporary exhibition.</b> The Museum holds regular lectures and film screenings in a cinema located in the building\'s basement.</string>
    <string name="orange_background">Orange background</string>
    <string name="vistula_header">Vistula</string>
    <string name="vistula_header_body_text">Warsaw’s new \"district\"</string>
    <string name="vistula_body_text">One would be hard-pressed to imagine Warsaw’s cityscape without the Vistula - the river has greatly impacted the city’s development and remains a source of numerous attractions for tourists and local residents alike. Outdoor events, beaches, water taxis, bicycle and pedestrian trails - to name just a few. Water sports lovers, families with young children and those seeking peace, quiet, and nature - everyone will find something to enjoy.</string>
    <string name="vistula_sail_down"><b>You can sail down the river!</b> The Pliszka, Słonka, and Wilga ferries will take you to the other side of Vistula in a matter of minutes - and they’re free! To enjoy an entirely new view of Warsaw, it’s worth taking the 90-minute water tram trip. Got the whole day off? Take the river boat to Serock.</string>
    <string name="vistula_sail_down_page"><u>www.ztm.waw.pl</u></string>
    <string name="vistula_urban_beaches"><b>Deckchairs, hammocks, ball game courts, places for bonfires</b> - urban beaches have a lot to offer.</string>
    <string name="vistula_facilities"><b>Gruba Kaśka (Plump Cathy) and Chudy Wojtek (Skinny Wojtek)</b> are the two Vistula facilities that have a job to do. Kaśka is the green tower in the middle of the river - the largest infiltration well in Europe. Wojtek is the boat charged with the task of loosening sediment at Kaśka’s feet.</string>
    <string name="vistula_fountain_park"><b>Water, Light, Sound shows</b> in the Multimedia Fountain Park, on Vistula’s left bank at the foot of the Old Town. On summer weekends (Fridays and Saturdays), a unique performance begins on the watery screen; lasers, animation and music blend into a colourful spectacle. For schedule details, visit</string>
    <string name="vistula_fountain_park_page"><u>www.estrada.com.pl</u></string>
    <string name="vistula_animals"><b>Wild animals in their natural habitat.</b> The Vistula’s river banks are home to many bird and mammal species. With a little patience and luck, you can see deer, wild boar, beavers, cormorants, hummingbirds, egrets and many other living things.</string>
    <string name="deep_orange_background">Deep orange background</string>
    <string name="pge_narodowy_header">PGE Narodowy stadium</string>
    <string name="pge_narodowy_header_body_text">Emotions guaranteed!</string>
    <string name="pge_narodowy_body_text">The stadium was built for the 2012 Euro Football Championship in the place of the historic 10th Anniversary Stadium (the \"Relay Race\" sculpture is to remind about the former facility). It is one of the most innovative constructions of this type in Europe. It combines the functions of a stadium and an arena for cultural events and as such is a venue of matches, concerts, numerous gigs, fairs and conferences. The National Stadium is buzzing with life all year, in wintertime too!</string>
    <string name="pge_narodowy_whole_stadium">The whole stadium: you can choose between the Footballer’s Route and any of the other extensive selection of special tours. For more information and the tour schedule, visit</string>
    <string name="pge_narodowy_whole_stadium_page"><u>www.en.pgenarodowy.pl/our-place/visiting-the-stadium</u></string>
    <string name="pge_narodowy_grounds"><b>Stadium grounds</b> - open seven days a week, dawn till dusk. An ideal place for rollersbladers or those who want to take a walk. It’s a popular venue for family and sports events, as well as other spontaneous events. A summer-zone has been organised around the stadium, with hammocks hung in trees as well as a go-carting track: the only asphalt track in Warsaw open daily to all.</string>
    <string name="pge_narodowy_cinema"><b>An open-air drive-in cinema</b> screens films in the summer on the stadium’s grounds. Films are shown on weekends, mid-June until mid-September.</string>
    <string name="pge_narodowy_capacity"><b>The stadium has a capacity of 58,000.</b> The stadium’s spire is 70 m tall, and four huge LED screens cover an area of more than 200 m2 . The stadium has been fitted with 550 km of cables - the exact distance from Warsaw to Szczecin along the E-30. The stadium’s cubature is more than 1,000,000 m3 - more than the Palace of Culture and Science with all adjoining rooms.</string>
</resources>
